All right, there's a whole bunch of new PID tuning softwares out there
but are they really PID tuning softwares?
Well, not all of them.
A good bit of them
these you can see on the screen, are really PID analysis softwares.
They take your black box logs
and your flight from your tuning session,
and it will... Go through and analyze the log data
give you step response, spectrographs
all the stuff you can see down here
down below to help you analyze the flight characteristics
and do the tuning yourself, really.
And many of these
if not all of them, are really based on the OG PID toolbox
which has been out for years by Brian White.
PID Toolbox used to be open source and freely available.
Now it's a part of his Patreon subscription for $6 a month
or just $6 for one month if you want to grab it that way.
So it's not really expensive in any way and shape or form.
And it's been out there.
It's the first one I'm aware of in the FPV community, at least
that looked at step response
and a number of other things.
It really begs the question if these other ones
are not just really iterations
of it taking the open source code that was there at the time
and vibe coding them into another package shape or form.
That all being said
after going through these
there's a number of differences between them all
and a number of unique
and good features on some of them.
So in this video
we're going to continue the series
and go through the software that you see up here
and kind of give you my thoughts on what's good, bad
what doesn't work
what does work really well
and just kind of give you a breakdown of everything.
A lot of these are web-based UI apps
so you can just go to a certain website and it's all there.
You can load your logs, so very easy.
You don't have to install things.
And we will compare them against the OG PID toolbox
to see what the results give.
Do they give the same result?
Because this is kind of tried and true and tested.
Brian is definitely an expert tuner
and really knows what he's doing.
By and large, like I said
he's probably the one that I would think developed the core basis of this
that the rest are kind of a... a derivative of to begin with.
Now before we get started
what we're going to be doing is loading some log files in
and it's going to be of this quadcopter
which we used in the last video in this series.
In the last video
we looked at the different input types,
wobble, chirp, of just sharp step inputs
and what some of the differences are
that you get in step response.
The conclusion of that testing
at least to me,
was that just implementing sharp stick inputs produced better results
or more accurate results for step response tools like this
over here in your flight analysis for your pits.
So just doing sharp stick inputs.
Now, if you haven't seen that video,
go ahead and check out the playlist down below.
We'll have that.
And then I also make a link to an old video I have.
about doing sharp stick inputs for pit analysis.
So it kind of comes back to that.
The chirp and the wobble are good for repeatability
but the sharp stick inputs generally just
do better at capturing the data better
for getting good analysis for your
step response graphs for things like this.
So that's what we're going to be using
and that's why we're using that.
And again, this is the quadcopter it was on.
We're going to have this tuned, untuned, and see some differences.
So since PID Toolbox is the OG
let's start with the OG.
PID Toolbox is, again, developed by Brian White.
I think it was developed in 2018
so it's been out there for quite a while.
I believe before COVID.
Time flies.
As I mentioned before
PID Toolbox used to be an open source software.
He kind of rolled that into his Patreon subscription for PID Toolbox Pro
which is the only thing under development.
So if you're interested in it
you would check out his Patreon
and I'll put the links down below.
For, I think it's $6
and change a month or just one month
you can download PID Toolbox
and install it on your system.
Obviously, you won't get updates if you'd stop your subscription.
You'd have to re-up the subscription and get new updates for it.
But you get other things beyond that.
Brian does weekly webinars where you can connect.
You can ask him stories or ask him for advice
ask him how PID Toolbox.
He has a number of videos on the software out there,
which... A lot of these other platforms don't have that.
You can get a hold of Brian.
He's in the community.
You can see him around.
He does professional tuning if you wanted that as well.
He does a lot of cine lifters, so on and so forth.
So he is readily available, tried and true, trusted resource
, has been in the community for a while, contributes to Betaflight.
So this whole like, hey, it's paid, that's bad, well
if that's not for you
then it's not for you
but it was definitely an inspiration.
I think PID Toolbox is an inspiration
for almost all of these other packages.
So with PID Toolbox
you do need to download and install it.
It is available for Windows easily, Mac a little less easily.
He does have that available now, though.
You have to do a couple things to get it to work
but he has instructions for it.
And I believe Linux is available in Linux as well.
So it's not a web-based UI.
You have to install it.
There is versions available.
He's looking at doing some AI assistant stuff in the next release
but he's vetting it.
He knows what the AI should be giving back.
So he's very skeptical and really trying to vet
is it giving back good data?
He doesn't want it to be a gimmick.
He wants it to be actual real health.
And that's some of the benefit with, again, PID Toolbox and Brian.
He's an expert in the area
and he's not there just trying to to make a buck.
He's trying to provide value.
So anyways, install PID Toolbox.
The interface looks like this.
You can open a log.
It supports all kinds of different firmware
from Betaflight to iNav, RGPilot
I believe KISS as well.
I'd have to look.
But it supports all the different firmwares out there.
You can open multiple logs
and then you can kind of pick them here and look between them.
This is the actual log traces.
Most of these softwares work very similar to this.
And I'm not going to go through top to bottom
on all these softwares and all the features
, but just to give an idea of the PID tuning part of it
you can run a step response tool.
And in that step response tool
you can run one or multiple logs.
So I can look at this for this is tuned.
This is untuned.
I can run those together at the same time and see the difference.
I actually had those, the one run.
So I have to hit reset and run it again.
But you can see this is this quad in red tuned.
The orange is untuned.
It's just the default
and then we have a little overshoot here.
It's detecting that.
There is some Y correction stuff that you need to do
generally in my experience
to get it to work correctly.
And then there's some other settings in here
for, like, how big of a window.
Essentially, this is a window that goes through the log
and it's looking at a two-second gap in time as it runs through the log
and it's looking for stepped inputs.
When you're looking at these graphs
another point I wanted to point out with this
that we're going to see in other software as well
is that it's not just one.
You're looking at an average by default.
So if I click the raw button here
this is all the data that it's looking at.
Then it averages to that one line that you see.
So you can see we get a way variety of step response stuff here.
And again, it's just averaging that out.
It's almost like if I zoom out far enough
it would average down to that one line.
So with step responses
you gotta keep that in mind.
And I'll talk more about that if you're interested in really
my true opinion of step response tools and what to look at.
You're gonna have to wait to the end of the video
and I'll talk about those ins and outs.
So keep that in mind
and that's how you can see it in PID Toolbox with this raw.
You can see all the different ones here.
Some softwares, I like the way they do it better than PID Toolbox for this
and I'll show you that in a little bit.
That's the long and the short.
You can change this window.
There's guides.
I really like this where you can actually click the button here
and it actually shows you the Betaflight slider setup
for each of these, which is awesome.
I wish other softwares... would have this
and they don't.
So that's really cool.
That's a really cool feature.
And again, I'm not going to go through all the pieces with this
but there is a spectrum analysis tool here as well to look at
PID noise, or not PID noise, your filter setup and quadcopter.
vibrations and tweaking your filters out
and all that kind of stuff.
And a common plot for that is the vibrations versus throttle
and this is the raw
this is the filter gyro, D-term raw
you see how much more vibration comes out because
the D-term amplifies it, and then after the D-term filters.
So you can see how the notch
and RPM filters are taking out the motor band and this resonance.
Spike here, things of that nature.
So that's how you kind of use these tools.
And again, a lot of these softwares
almost all of them have these very exact same same stuff.
There's little tweaks around the edges.
Generally, this is the complement of tools they get.
There's a I'm going to say that I'm actually the inspiration for this.
I think Brian wrote this on his own
but I had Excel files like back in 2017
that mapped all the filter, maybe even earlier.
I guess it was 2017 that mapped all the filters out
and the phase delay between them on.
And, and, uh, so this is really cool.
Uh, this is a really cool thing.
So without rambling on too much
let's move on to the next one.
So the next firmware is PIDscope.
So PIDscope is admittedly a derivative of PIDtoolbox.
When PIDtoolbox went into Brian's Patreon
people would say behind a paywall
a gentleman grabbed the source code from PIDtoolbox
and moved it into Octave.
PIDtoolbox uses MATLAB.
PIDscope uses Octave.
It essentially looks exactly the same, works pretty much the exact same.
It has the slider tool.
It does have the filter simulation and some of the stuff.
I would say the user interface is even a little nicer.
So if I look at this
it's just this panel is a little bit nicer
displayed in this PID scope than it is in PID Toolbox.
So Octave and... MATLAB are not generally
software that is made for distribution.
It's more for university analysis and things of that nature.
So when it gets into the graphic-y part
they're a little clunky
and that's why
because they're made for scientists
and stuff and engineers that are not
really hung up about that kind of stuff.
They're trying to dig into data.
and really figure things out.
So that's why you see that.
Admittedly, one thing with the PID scope
is it is a little slower and more clunky.
So it runs a little bit slower.
It's not too slow, which is
do you notice it, than PID Toolbox?
But it has a lot of the same features.
So you can see here what you get for a step response.
It's... This is where it's a little different.
Like, you can see I'm running that same log
sharp stick inputs only, tuned, and that graphic looks
way different than what you get in PID Toolbox.
So just putting them side by side
you can see the huge difference between the two.
Now, there is stuff that I could probably change
down here to make it look closer-ish
like the Y correction wasn't turned on.
But I shouldn't have to do that at the end of the day.
And I'm not going to go through all the different little things
here to see if I get the same result.
So that's a factor.
I don't know why there's a differential.
If I had to trust one over the other
I'm going to trust PID Toolbox.
I'm not saying, you know
maybe the developer of PIDscope can chime in
but it's the same log.
I'm getting two different results, so why?
And this is something more closely aligned to what I would expect to see.
This is a well-tuned quad
and when I look at that versus the untuned...
Or I should be able to just click on this and hit run.
I see that little blip
and that's what this has at default.
It has a little bit of an overshoot on the roll axis.
If I do the same thing in the PID scope
you kind of see that
but it's not as straightforward to me
because it looks like you have overshoot on both axes.
Same data, just analyzing it differently.
So maybe there's some settings here I'd
have to adjust to make that look correctly
but I shouldn't have to do that.
It looks like that's right there.
The sharp maneuvers looks like it is the one that you'd have to click on.
So it's only looking at sharp stick inputs and not all the inputs.
And maybe that's the differential there.
So you can see up here
if you can see that
I can see it closely.
This is like looking at 108 inputs
and 88 where Pit Toolbox is looking at, in its default, 483.
So it's looking at a lot more inputs there.
Now, if I uncheck this sharp maneuvers.
and let that rerun.
Now, well, it's even looking at less.
52.
I can't even see the other number in here.
So, yeah.
Other things in here that might play a factor is degrees per second
it's looking at versus the other.
Like, this is the range of degrees per second it's looking at.
So, now we're getting up a higher amount.
So, anyways, again, I'm not trying to vet these softwares for accuracy.
And, well, to some extent I am.
And... you know figure out everything
but those are some of my general observations
that if you're looking at this don't just accept the defaults
there's you might need a noodle with it a little bit more
and look at your count over here to to see
that it's giving you a decent step response graphs there another thing like
when you run the plots here in the frequency
versus throttle The stuff's not aligned.
Like this is under
this is the D term.
This is the D term pre-filter gyro.
So again, this is the graphical stuff that is a little, like I said
even PID toolbox is not great graphics wise.
PID scope is much similar, is very similar.
MATLAB and Octave are two kind of analytical
softwares that these are kind of based upon.
And it's not strong for graphical user interface nicety.
PIDscope is one that is free.
You do have to download it
and you just run a batch file and then it runs.
You have to have an installer for Octave
that it needs to put into your computer as well
which is fairly sizable.
So both of those packages,
PIDtoolbox and PIDscope, our download-based software.
The rest of these are going to be web-based.
Okay, so this next one is
PidTuna. PidTuna, again, is web-based.
You can see it up here
and I will drop, of course, these links down below.
I really like PidTuna.
There's some cool things in it
so let me show you what it's got here.
So first of all, it's web-based.
I like that.
I can just go to the site
and go from there and click the logs.
You can load as many logs as, well, not as many
but you can load multiple log files here as well
and compare them against each other.
If you just have one log selected
I like the step response
which is going to be over here under step response.
It shows you the different lines kind of faded back
and it shows you that average.
So you're mindful and conceive like there's big deviations here.
What is based on that average?
Like look at the y'all access compared to these other ones.
There's a couple things in here as well.
Just like in PID Toolbox
I didn't look in PID Scope
but you can adjust that window size.
So you can go from anywhere from 0.25 seconds up to 3 seconds.
That's what those milliseconds to seconds conversion is.
And I think its default was 2,000
which would be 2 seconds, the same as PID Toolbox.
You can also look at the min
and max window for step response input.
So you can see if I move this down
like this is the minimum that it's... excluding so
I'm taking this down to any stepped inputs at 45 degrees per second
or an up it's going to look into that
and you can see how small step inputs makes this kind of worse
and it does have a default here
which you can easily click like that's nice
that you can click back to the default the auto
when you click on two logs here it shows both
and I get what I would expect to see between these two the the tuned
and untuned it's actually a little bit more accurate
it looks to me, for the untune
where I have this little bit of this oscillation here on the roll axis.
That's essentially what this 5-inch gets with just Betaflight defaults.
It's a pretty good tune
but it's not perfect.
There's P-term overshoot and flips and rolls and things of that nature.
So that's picking that up and showing that.
It's snappy, as you can see
and then you can also adjust your window size
here if you have to clip some stuff out.
You can click full log here
and look at the full log if you don't want to clip things out.
There's a scorecard tool in here
so you can kind of see what it's seeing as good versus bad.
So this is the tune log
and it's saying, hey
everything looks pretty good here, which is accurate
except for motor balance
which is also accurate.
The motor balance isn't great
and I'll talk about that in a second.
It also has available here
that you can see that the default is okay.
It's yellow.
It's basically saying your step response
and your tracking, your rise time, your overshoot
your latency aren't great.
They're mid.
They're yellow, which is accurate.
You can click on these things
and it takes you right to the window that it's kind of talking about.
So it's kind of neat for a heads-up analysis
of what... uh what you may want to look at
and you can consider uh there's tracking plots just like input toolbox
and the other things i talked about you can look at the raw uh you can
look at just the pid terms themselves there 's
like a thousand different ways to to look
at different little aspects of it there 's an
i - term saturation tool where you can see
if your i - term it 's not such a thing for beta flight anymore
but it could be for like kiss or uh even INAV
probably definitely RG Pilot, I would think
to see if you're getting I-term saturation.
Basically, you're leaning too heavily on I-term
to keep the thing in balance.
There's a motor analysis tool here as well
that will look at your different motors
and seeing if you're getting to motor saturation with your input.
So if you see a lot of it
you're going to have A bad step response graph
or bad tune just because your quad is underpowered.
Your motors are too small for the weight and rotation.
Again, for 5-inch quads
it hardly ever happens.
It's not that big
although it is a thing
and I'll show you that.
For big quads, that's a big deal.
because we're skipping over
that a lot like hey are your motors saturated
because that overshoot you might see
in that step response that could be just
because your your motors can't keep up
you're not tuning that out you need bigger motors
or reduce the moment of inertia on this craft somehow
or reduce your rates pick one motor balance tool now
this is off on this specific log you
can see here it 's on this top log here it 's i do n't know why it did
n't pick this up correctly it 's not that
out of balance this is more closely accurate uh it
does do a better job i do n't think
it was this tool was probably another tool at showing
that hey the the back motors are working
harder than the front motors on this quad
and then they do
and that's semi-normal.
But it's not ideal.
There's nothing I can really fix on it.
It is what it is.
I already have a GoPro in the front
so the back motors are
just because the thing's going like this
and it's pushing forward that way
the back motors just work a little bit harder.
But it's not wrong about it
which is good input.
There's a nice little GPS function here that you can actually
if you have your GPS on, like I do
and it logs that now in the latest Betaflight
you can actually play through
and see the quad and
where it went and all that kind of stuff
which you could use for different things if you want.
We already talked about the step response tool.
There's the latency in here that can show you latency information.
I didn't really dig into this too much.
There's some full spectrum things.
information here the the sim filter stuff is here
as well i don't think this works exactly right uh
because i'm seeing things like that i don't know that
the filter sim stuff's that widely used anyways but um that outside
so i don't know that this is this is great and working
well There's spectrogram tools in here as well.
Probably, I would say, not as nice as PID Toolbox or the other one.
This is kind of the full flight log.
You can change this to raw
and this is kind of the motor trace.
So you can see the vibrations.
Like, this is throughout the entire flight
and you can see the motor.
Like, this is a ramp up to full
throttle dropped, ramped up to full throttle dropped
and then this is all the different vibrations.
This is basically the motor noise up here.
You can see where there's resonance spikes
kind of throughout the flight as well.
I don't know that this is too helpful
but that's what it is.
You can change some things on here to make it
a little bit more fine fidelity in what you're seeing down there.
Again, another spec for motor trace stuff and vibrations,
and then some tuning settings down here.
If you have one log selected
it just looks at that information.
If you have two or more logs selected, probably just two
it kind of shows you some differentials between the two logs
that you have turned on there.
And then you can also hit differential here
and kind of see the differentials between those two logs as well.
So like if I turn off one of the logs
I don't get a diff.
But if I turn on that
you can see like, oh
this log has higher, you know, red is decreased, green is increased.
So green in this case is kind of bad.
You have more latency in the default
than you do in the tuned one, things like that.
So like I talked about, a lot of information.
It's quick.
It's web-based.
You can bring it up.
I like the step response piece probably the most.
I think it's a quick way to look at step response.
You can load up the stuff.
It's snappy and motor balance looks fairly good there
except for that one example
where it was off for some reason.
on that one log.
But yeah, I think PIDtuna is a pretty good
free web-based solution to check out.
Okay, the next one is going to be PIDpulse.
So PIDpulse is also a web-based solution.
It's one log at a time.
You can click on it
and then hit and open that log
and it will show you the step response.
Again, here, let's just look here.
I don't love what I'm seeing for the step response here
as you can hopefully have a mind's eye
of what the default looked like before.
This is awfully wavy.
Now, it should have this overshoot because this is the default
and there's not a lot.
I don't see any things that I can really adjust here to adjust any of that.
It's kind of
that's what you got.
So not as adjustable as the PIDtuna, PIDtoolbox or the PIDscope.
You can click into here to see the individual step responses.
So that's good.
You can just click that button on each one of them.
And there is some, you know
you can kind of change the window size here
to see, you know, kind of zoom in upfront.
You can look at one axis versus another.
You can share your analysis stuff with somebody.
So that's pretty cool.
There is a drop-down here to look at throttle versus noise
and it will do the spectrograms
and spectrographs and stuff like that for that.
So that's kind of what that looks like.
And there's a number of other things, time versus noise,
D-term, RPM noise, a bunch of stuff with noise.
It does look at motor balance.
Here I'm looking at the default.
It's basically saying here this was the one.
That shows that the pitch access is... you know, off balance here.
And it talks about the rear motors are working noticeably harder.
The FC is holding the nose up.
The GC sits somewhere aft.
And so that's cool.
Like it gives you some input here on that.
It has a high confidence level, supposedly.
So that's a neat analysis that it has there.
But going back to the step response on this
I think one of the coolest things that this has
is you can actually hit calculate PIDs.
and it will, and this can take some time.
I've already clicked it on this
but this can take some time, like multiple minutes, maybe five.
It can take some time
I've noticed sometimes.
But this will allow you to say, hey
this is the current
and then you can make adjustments to this to say
what if I make these PID setting changes
will it what what would it change to
basically saying it's essentially saying my i term
is too high here so that's very cool
i love that
and then you can hit this uh find recommended pids so you may say well
this is not a just a pit analysis this is a pid tuning software it's like
yeah
well this isn't that accurate so it's very cool
but If I switch my PIDs to the Tune PIDs
so this is the default.
Let me go and put in what my Tune PIDs are
and you know what that looked like.
It looked like it was perfect step response in PID Toolbox,
well, not so much in PIDscope, but in PIDtuna and the other ones.
And we'll see... What if I put those PIDs in here?
That should show me that same really good step response.
Let's see what it actually gives me.
So now I've input the tuned PIDs
and you saw what those step response looks like
and this is what it's telling me.
So this doesn't really lead me to the tuned quad.
I think the biggest thing that this
is probably missing is that Betaflight has iTerm Relax.
So iTerm Relax basically negates the iTerm
overshoot when... You do sharp stick input.
So this may be more accurate if you would have that turned off
but nobody has that turned off.
It's not turned off by default.
Why would you ever turn it off?
So that's my guess of why this is off.
You can also hit recommended PIDs here as well.
Again, this can take a little bit of time
but I'm telling you, too
it's not going to come to.
these numbers and it doesn't, yeah
it's not coming up with a great tune to be input to begin with.
So here after waiting probably a minute or so
this is the PID tune it's recommending.
which is odd because it's still showing like an overshoot here
but that's not right.
First of all, the D term on the pitch
needs to go up for overshooting issues.
Yeah, this would just be chasing.
I mean, you can just be chasing your tail.
Now, to the defense
this uses for guidance only, safety check, all that kind of good stuff.
So, very cool concept.
I like this.
this thing where it can do that
and you can move stuff around.
I just wish it worked a little bit better.
But yeah, go check it out.
I think it's worth your time to at least explore it and take a look.
Again, it's web-based.
It's pretty easy to click on it, load a log
and nuts around with it yourself and see what you think.
Now, the final one here is PidLab.
So PidLab is another tool, web-based.
You can see the link up top here.
You can also, it's a web app
so you can click it here
and it would put a little cached version
on your computer so you could use it without the internet.
It has a little dashboard so you can load your log.
Some things with this is I've noticed
that it can take a while to load a log.
Like some logs just load right up.
But Flight of Flight 4.0, well, Flight of Flight 2026.06.
They take a while to load, like a couple minutes.
I don't know why.
I don't know if my sample frequency was semi-high on them.
Maybe it's that.
I don't know.
The other ones don't take that long to load them.
And you can see once you load a larger log or I don't know
just a log with I don't know why it's taking longer on these.
I wouldn't say a larger log necessarily.
It's kind of really sluggish to move around here.
So let me pause for a second.
Well, long story short with PID Labs
it it does at the top say
the software is under development and may contain bugs.
So I'll give it that.
And it was something just sent to me as a trial.
Check it out.
It's free.
It's online.
You can see the web address up there.
I have trouble just getting logs to load.
Some of them, once they load
it's really sluggish to move through the program.
It does give recommendations based on what it sees
but the recommendations are, I think, AI slop.
Like the one it was like
there's high prop wash detected.
Turn your D gains down.
Set your... Oh, here we go, finally.
Set your some other stuff down.
And like here, um, set, so prop, severe prop wash
on the y'all access for like not normal, a normal thing
but then let's go set your D gain to zero
and y'all set your dynamic idle to 30
and then turn up your feed forward smoothing factor.
What the heck does that have to do?
With prop wash, that's most likely not on the yaw axis.
It's not prop wash based on the yaw axis.
Prop wash is like oscillating down through the, you know
it's basically the airfoil of the prop messing up.
And your yaw axis doesn't use that.
It's using moment of inertia and drag, wind drag.
So it's just, yeah.
These aren't good
so I think these are kind of AI slop.
It has all the other normal spectrograph stuff.
It's not that great.
You can see here the spectrograph is not...
This is the SEP response from this log.
This is not my log.
This is some older log that I got from helping somebody tune
so I don't... This is not really good.
I did load my own logs before
and they were all shaky like this.
Again, you can probably... change stuff in here
and tweak stuff to get it better.
But I shouldn't have to do that.
I shouldn't have to know like custom settings.
Nobody's gonna know that stuff.
The default should be pretty good.
And then if you're tweaking stuff up here
it should be like more advanced things that you wanna look at.
So not a really good one here.
So as promised, I told you I'd tell you what my favorite is.
My favorite for tuning is I use Black Box Explorer.
And the reason it's free
it's in Betaflight Configurator now.
It has some features the other ones don't have.
Like, for example, not many features
but one that I like a lot is that in the spectrographs
you can run frequency versus RPM versus frequency versus throttle.
And you can see that it makes a difference.
Like, you can see that straight line linear response
that you get versus RPM versus throttle.
It's like this curved response.
This curve response.
So you can see that we do get a pretty linear
response with our RPM increases for our quadcopter.
It's really just the throttle to the frequency
that you get a kind of a curved nonlinear response.
So like that's a little feature.
I think the biggest thing is that
when you're looking at your stepped inputs
what you can kind of see look like the same step response thing.
Like if you're looking at step response, well
this is the step response, right?
Going up and to one and across.
This is that step response right here.
you can see a lot of stuff with this like it's going up
we have barely a little this is untuned barely a little overshoot
but then there's like a little bit of wobble
now it's rotating at full rate rotation
and you can see we have some overshoot Most importantly
that when you look at stick tracking all by itself
you can look down here
and look at this part of it.
So if I zoom in and I do my exaggeration
you can see here and confirm things like, hey
this overshoot that we have down here
is that because the motors can't keep up?
The answer is no
because you can see we're not over, you know
the motor commands aren't at 100%.
So it's not oversaturation of the motors that is making this overshoot.
It is just tuning is the problem.
Vice versa, can you see here the same thing?
Like, why is there this big delay?
I can tune that delay out with feed forward.
No, you cannot.
You can make it a little bit better
but you're not going to tune it all the way out.
Why?
Your motors are fully saturated right here.
This is you might be a little bit better
but you're not.
You know, once you crank up feed forward and whatnot
you're kind of to some extent
that's as good as you're going to get it.
Feed forward does help because it makes it enter the move faster.
But if you have your feed forward up, you know
I don't have feed forward on here.
if i had feed forward up
and i was tweaking that i could see like
am i chasing the rabbit am i hitting motor saturation all over the place
if i am that's as good as you're gonna get unless i put bigger motors on
or reduce the uh the moment of inertia
so that's that's a huge thing to me um black box wise
that you can just see all that here it's like all heads up information
uh right away um you're not looking at like having to interpret graphs
you're just looking at it right here
Basically looking at the, I would say, raw data.
Outside of that, like I said before, Brian Weitz
with PID Toolbox, of course, and off the service.
If you're looking for a higher level of service
that comes along with his Patreon.
And the PIDtuna.
I think the PIDtuna is really cool just for a quick.
I like the interface.
It's snappy.
I like some of the features of the interface I talked about.
So that is my roundup for PID analysis software.
In the next video
we're going to talk about PID.
So that will be a hot take.
Are the recommendations good?
I am skeptical that they will be good.
Just, you know, AI speaks with confidence, confidently wrong
and you chase your tail.
But a lot of people do swear by it as well
you'll see out there.
So we'll be checking them out.
If you want to make sure you don't miss that
go ahead and make sure you're subscribed down below.
Links to all these are available down below,
and also the playlist as well for this whole series.
Thanks, everybody.
See you in the next one.